Contact

PTY 31002 2250 NW 114th Ave., Unit 1P Miami FL 33172-3652 831-214-2990 (Mobile) jordan@jordanzimmerman.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ jordanzimmerman (LinkedIn) github.com/randgalt/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Java

Distributed Systems
ZooKeeper

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Elementary)

Publications

Curator and Exhibitor: A better way to use and manage Apache ZooKeeper

Apache ZooKeeper Backup, a Treatise

Apache ZooKeeper Made Simpler with Curator

J2EE Technology in Practice: Building Business Applications with the Java 2 Platform, Enterprise Edition

A Memory Manager for the Rest of

Patents

Multi-vendor internet commerce system for e-commerce applications and methods therefore

Jordan Zimmerman

Senior Software Engineer / Contractor at Starburst Data Lisbon Metropolitan Area

Summary

Jordan Zimmerman has had a distinguished career as a distributed systems and cloud developer. Formerly he was on the Platform team at Netflix. He created Apache Curator, the popular Apache ZooKeeper client as well as other open source projects. He has been published in the Software Developer's Journal, the Cloudera Blog, an Addison-Wesley book and many other publications. He and his wife live near Lisbon, Portugal.

Experience

Starburst Data
Senior Software Engineer Contractor
April 2020 - Present (1 year 6 months)

- * Microservices
- * Distributed systems
- * Presto

Grubhub

2 years 1 month

Team Lead Contractor September 2019 - March 2020 (7 months)

- * Technical direction, mentoring, hiring
- * Java SOA
- * Microservices
- * Cassandra
- * Distributed systems

Technical Lead Contractor March 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 7 months)

- * Technical direction, mentoring, hiring
- * Java SOA
- * Microservices
- * Cassandra

* Distributed systems

Elastic

Cloud Engineer Contractor
January 2016 - February 2018 (2 years 2 months)

- * Member of the Cloud core team
- * Part of platform team writing and deploying Elastic's cloud offering
- * Java and Scala Services
- * Docker, Elasticsearch, ZooKeeper, sbt, Vagrant, AWS

Blue Jeans Network

Senior Software Engineer Contractor September 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 4 months)

- * Platform team
- * Java/REST services
- * Integrating Netflix OSS libraries
- * ZooKeeper

Qubole

Senior Software Engineer Contractor December 2013 - September 2014 (10 months)

Member of team building cloud based Hadoop/Hive framework

Riot Games

Senior Software Engineer Contractor July 2013 - December 2013 (6 months)

- * Big data and distributed cloud computing for the world's biggest online game, League of Legends.
- * Java REST services
- * Integrating Netflix OSS libraries

Netflix

Senior Platform Engineer April 2011 - July 2013 (2 years 4 months)

- * Helped build the foundation shared libraries and infrastructure components
- that enables Netflix development in the Cloud
- * Member Platform team
- * Java services and libraries
- * Initiated the Netflix OSS project by open sourcing Curator now Apache Curator as well as Exhibitor and Governator

Proofpoint

Architect

March 2010 - April 2011 (1 year 2 months)

Software Architect in the Cloud Services group. Implemented a sharded, cloud-based Lucene search service. Helped architect new SaaS platform.

SHOP.COM

Principal Software Architect 1997 - March 2010 (13 years)

Architect of AMOS – Altura Merchant Operating System, e-commerce platform used for a variety of websites. Helped transition Altura Software from vendor of developer tools to a dot-com.

Altura Software Senior Software Engineer 1992 - 1997 (5 years)

Senior Engineer in charge of Windows to Macintosh project. Technical Account Manager/Senior Engineer for several Macintosh to Windows projects. System design and implementation of Windows to Macintosh porting library. System design and implementation of QuickHelp - the WinHelp compatible online help system for Macintosh. QuickHelp was used by Apple Computer for its Macintosh Programmers Toolbox Assistant.

Symantec Corporation Software Engineer 1991 - 1992 (1 year)

Implemented major components of Q&A for the Macintosh, a flat-file database with integrated word processing. Lead Engineer of an eight person team.

Draw Engine - sophisticated color "draw-type" graphics module. Design Module - user-customizable forms module. Memory Management. Instituted source code control system. Decision maker regarding technical issues. Responsible for developing engineering plan.

Screenplay Systems Software Engineer 1988 - 1990 (2 years)

Sole engineer on version 2.0 of Movie Magic Scheduling, the industry standard project management tool for the Motion Picture industry. Designed and implemented new functionality. Made the code ANSI C compliant. Ported code to MS/DOS from Macintosh. Added Desk Accessory and Control Panel

features to the porting library. UNIX development experience. MS/DOS and Windows development experience. Wrote portable memory manager for Macintosh and Windows.

Education

Van Nuys High School (1979 - 1982)

Fulton Jr. High (1978 - 1981)